<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>curtomil</title>
    <description>socia(l / ble) scientist</description>
    <link>https://curtomil.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="https://curtomil.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Is it true that not paying for free software is cheating the system?</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2015/02/27/free-software-payments</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2015/02/27/free-software-payments</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Some Baffling Publications</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I read a lot of books, so I care a lot about how they are written. Sometimes, the writing is bad, and sometimes the writing is good. The writing is not everything though, and a few times, it is the editing which is bad. Here are some examples of terrible editing. 
The first example baffles me particularly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-images/sartre_existentialisme.png&quot; alt=&quot;L&#39;existentialisme est un humanisme&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This passage is taken from the French edition of &lt;em&gt;Existentialism is a humanism&lt;/em&gt; by Jean-Paul Sartre. It comes from the collection &lt;em&gt;Folio essais&lt;/em&gt;, which I assumed specialised in short essays until I saw that Simone de Beauvoir’s &lt;em&gt;Le deuxième sexe&lt;/em&gt;—a rather large book—was part of that same collection. What could possibly warrant such a small text column? The two column design starts from good intentions: to summarise the paragraph’s idea to allow the reader a cursory glance once he has read the book. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that it makes the main text impossible to read! It’s frustrating to to go down a line so fast. And some of the summaries are not really interesting (some are titled ‘an example’). Another reason for this design is to make the book small enough and accessible to act as a manifesto, in a way similar than Strunk and White’s &lt;em&gt;The elements of style&lt;/em&gt;. But why not make the book bigger then? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not the only version of the book available. In French, as well, was a 1970 edition that had a much larger main text. I suppose this one was accepted by Sartre (the &lt;em&gt;Folio essais&lt;/em&gt; version was published in 1996, well after the author’s passing). The Folio series are usually (literally) pocket sized book, and that is generally a great idea, but not always. Some books are too lengthy to comfortably read in that format; the small size is only camouflaged by the large depth that makes it impractical. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example of publishing that is usually disliked by some colleagues is Law’s and Mol’s book &lt;em&gt;The body multiple&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-images/mol_body_multiple.png&quot; alt=&quot;The body multiple&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice, at the bottom, the text with a sans-serif font? The main text is accompanied by a sort of guide explaining the conditions of the investigation and the methodology taken. On each page, these two texts are displayed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually like it. The problem for some is that the two texts don’t talk about the same thing, or are not directly related. Personnally, I prefer it that way; had it been directly complimentary, I would have felt obliged to read both at the same time. Not here, I just casually glance at the text on the bottom, keep calm, and carry on. Perhaps it’s because I tend to read books slowly, or like getting distracted. But frankly, it has guts to try something like this, acting as a practical analogy of the multiple in the text which follows its own lines and directions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of books that just re-print—even with an old type-writer font. I don’t mind so much, but there is no evolution. Most of these books, for example, don’t provide an index. St a time when books are competing with articles (and losing ground to them), it’s sad so little effort is made to keep them floating. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-images/puf.png&quot; alt=&quot;Différence et répétition&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare the left page from the right… Look for the p’s especially… The font seems to have been washed away, it’s barely readable as it is. But the publisher is the French university presses holding many important texts written by professors. Even their recent financial difficulties doesn’t add up: this is the 12th edition! My guess is that the same image of the original edition (1968) has been used, and that’s it. It hasn’t changed at all from the first one—bugger all the typesetting advancements! It’s just a pity, especially compared to American or British university presses which seem to make a big effort in making their books easy to read. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I’m making a fuss and the typewriter font from the French university press does have some charm. But why leave the poor print quality? &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2015/02/25/Some-Baffling-Publications</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2015/02/25/Some-Baffling-Publications</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Internet of Things will be an Internet of Obsolete Junk&amp;#8594;</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And what about the instant purchase and upgrade fetishes that will add massive over-consumption to mass capitalism’s inexorable crises of overproduction? The internet of things will create a mountain of junk. Its electronic detritus will be untold.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Suddenly your light switch, toothbrush, trousers, tights, kettle, bedroom toys – and chopsticks – will be rendered useless thanks to software upgrades, otherwise known as built-in obsolescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, finally! An article that doesn’t rehash all the beautiful promises of the internet of things (usually meaning: of everything). The ecological consequences of ‘internetification’ will be painful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2015/02/19/The-internet-of-things-will-be-an-internet-of-obsolete-junk</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2015/02/19/The-internet-of-things-will-be-an-internet-of-obsolete-junk</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Les Chiens de Garde (Watchdogs)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Les Chiens de Garde&lt;/em&gt;—Watchdogs in English—by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Nizan&quot;&gt;Paul Nizan&lt;/a&gt; is an odd tale for contemporary times. The bottom-line (TL;DR) is that we are not only subject to scrutiny by defenders of morality, but are also made to think like they would want us to &lt;a href=&quot;#Nizan:2012ta&quot;&gt;(Nizan, 2012)&lt;/a&gt;. It might seem ludicrous in today’s democratic societies to wonder whether we are anybody’s ‘subjects’. After all and despite rising costs in academia, the number of people with education has never been this high. The elites are not the only ones capable of reaching the best degrees. Yet, there is a concentration of media around a few wealthy individuals that did not exist for much of the past century. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The books that usually treat such a monopoly of information are either historical accounts, or dystopian science-fiction (&lt;em&gt;Animal Farm&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Brave New World&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1984&lt;/em&gt;). Few of today’s popular cultural products, outside of philosophy, treat of a &lt;em&gt;present&lt;/em&gt;, active subjectification &lt;a href=&quot;#Guattari:1995te&quot;&gt;(Guattari, 1995)&lt;/a&gt;; the only that comes to mind right away is the movie &lt;em&gt;District 9&lt;/em&gt; where we see a normal guy acting on the orders of his superiors that he desperately tries to accommodate. After all, he wants to be well-liked. This is what &lt;em&gt;Les Chiens de Garde&lt;/em&gt; is about: an analysis of a caste completely unconcerned with the living conditions of its inferiors (or so are they deemed). Worse, these masses of inferiors must be channelled to productive uses (the superiors’ productive uses, to be precise). This is my brief review of the book. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;re-actualisation&quot;&gt;Re-actualisation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would a book from 1932 [&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:book&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:book&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;], written by a 27 year old Paul Nizan, be of any interest nowadays? This quote helpfully contextualises the book’s central arguments to today (my translation):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is not in vain that the jury of teaching fellows only asks candidates about Ideas. The Idea of truth. The Idea of reality. The Idea of justice. The Idea of progress. The Idea of the State. Should it not be verified that these future professors are capable and willing to do their duty and reveal that which lay in shadows?
&lt;a href=&quot;#Nizan:2012ta&quot;&gt;(Nizan, 2012, p. 79)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nizan harshly criticises the philosophers of his time (the 1930s and before) which, he argues, acted as watchdogs to the production of knowledge and the attribution of meaning. To talk of ‘Ideas’ with a big I, to capitalise the concepts, is to give them an unquestionable quality, a universal value that holds always true. The problem, according to Nizan, is that those values reflect necessarily those who are responsible for their production (and enjoyment): the &lt;em&gt;bourgeois&lt;/em&gt;. Although the term &lt;em&gt;bourgeois&lt;/em&gt; has lost a lot of weight since the events of May 68, it is still used widely, only in other forms. More contemporary terms would be the ‘1%’ from Occupy Wall Street, the ‘elites’, the ‘wealthy’ (from Piketty’s essays). This conception of the &lt;em&gt;bourgeois&lt;/em&gt; as both responsible for a society’s moral compass and the one who enjoys the fruits of that morality, is still very much with us. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-productive-bourgeois&quot;&gt;The Productive &lt;em&gt;Bourgeois&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with this &lt;em&gt;bourgeois&lt;/em&gt; control over the production of knowledge and meaning is a concentration of the valuation (and the values themselves) of things, of what is right and wrong, by those who profit themselves directly from the production. Citing Nietzsche in &lt;em&gt;The Dawn of Day&lt;/em&gt;, Nizan presents this argument more forcefully (again, my translation) &lt;a href=&quot;#Nietzsche:2012ta&quot;&gt;(Nietzsche, 2012)&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;F. Nietzsche had already seen that a business-minded society had to flee the possibilities of living and thinking dangerously: “The Moral Code of conduct of a business-minded society—Behind this principle of the moral conduct: the moral actions are the actions of sympathy towards the others, I see dominate the social instinct of fear that disguises itself as an intellectual endeavour: this instinct poses as superior principle the most important and the most central, that it must be taken from life anything that is dangerous or was previously thought as dangerous, and that everyone should help in this to the utmost of their strength. Only those actions that aim towards general security and the sensation of security are those that can be qualified as good.”
&lt;a href=&quot;#Nizan:2012ta&quot;&gt;(Nizan, 2012, p. 90)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this ring any bells? It seems this quote has not aged a bit. Nizan (and Nietzsche as well) do not claim that we should live dangerously in the physical sense, but that there is censorship over ideas simply because a handful of (powerful) people deem it ‘dangerous’. This is right inside Orwell’s &lt;em&gt;1984&lt;/em&gt; territory, where dangerous words are wiped from the vocabulary, and therefore, human consciousness. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other ideas, though, seem to have aged quite a bit. For example, Nizan is quite wary of the State, which is strange to hear from a 1930’s communist. According to him, the philosophers are the State’s clerical staff responsible for the reproduction of its political thought. It is their doing, their teaching which maintains the common man oppressed (or suppressed?). Today’s communists, instead, postulate themselves as defenders of public institutions, especially the schooling system. But Nizan seems to argue in favour of private entrepreneurship to impart educational material, far removed from the State’s hands and its potential power of manipulation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Nizan makes a forceful point: we have to be wary of concentrations of power—in some way, just as economics should be wary of monopolies—especially in those areas which concern the production of ethical values. On these values, and the way they are produced, depend further productions. It is this point which is most concerning: the worlds seems to converge around larger entities whose ethical pursuits are not clear. In the IT world, tech giants are buying companies left, right and center; the media are part of a few conglomerates owned by extremely wealthy people [&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:presse&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:presse&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;]; the universities are ever more dependent on public finances which are increasingly controlled and subject to bureaucracies which limit their emancipation; the Internet and the Web are sliding dangerously from citizen hands. Once dusted off a bit, Nizan’s words ring too true. A sad state of affair indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-critique-of-the-role-of-philosophy-and-sociology&quot;&gt;A Critique of the Role of Philosophy and Sociology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What to do according to Nizan?  Nizan almost specifically dedicates a chapter to this. His work affects the way research should, according to him, be carried out. He comes to argue for a closer link with the common men, and how they come into being. He questions their knowledge and the sources of their views, the positions they find themselves in and the possibilities they have to escape their situation. He asks that research be close to those that suffer, those that have little force to make their voices heard in a very phenomenological fashion (my translation):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We have to ask every man how he perceives the elements of his life: his activity, his joy, his sadness all lay on top of this perception. We then have to look for the sources of his perception, if it were born from a direct experience or whether it is an idea harped on by some teacher who is stranger to his life. 
&lt;a href=&quot;#Nizan:2012ta&quot;&gt;(Nizan, 2012, p. 131)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This experience echoes Zuboff’s work when questioning the introduction of the computer in various industrial and service-oriented sectors &lt;a href=&quot;#Zuboff:1989ul&quot;&gt;(Zuboff, 1989)&lt;/a&gt;. Nizan, equally, would have been worried about the space given to people and how the expectations from the elites would have influenced them &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; their thinking processes. In some way, both these works are an up-ending of the traditional values of Taylorism: both try to render visible the changes and the obstacles to those that Taylorism made invisible. For Zuboff, those were workers in the industry, treated as automatons; for Nizan, those that were told that all was well and were never listened to. These, sadly, have remained unseen except in that research which made the effort to go look for them, those &lt;em&gt;othered&lt;/em&gt;, rendered strangers by those more powerful. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last chapter, Nizan gets carried away. Perhaps too much the fruit of his time—he dreamt of revolutions—and so the tone sounds somewhat naive now that we can look back at the events that promised so much freedom and delivered too few. Yet, his analysis of the situation remains true despite the 80 or so years that separate the first edition from the newest one. Despite the grim situation of an economically depressed Europe, there is hope in an energised citizenship, concerned about its role and participation in democracy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 
In some ways, the critique serves as a wakeup call, firstly, from a dependency on irrelevant philosophies so detached of the world of the common man; and secondly, in favour of a grounded engagement of philosophy that could provide realistic answers. 


Some interesting quotes (my translation):

&gt; When the bourgeois ideas were seen as the productions of an eternal reason, when they had lost the staggering character of a historical production, they then got imbued with the greatest chance to survive and resist any assault. 
(Nizan 1932, p. 88)
 --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Nizan:2012ta&quot;&gt;Nizan, P. (2012). &lt;i&gt;Les Chiens de Garde&lt;/i&gt;. Agone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Guattari:1995te&quot;&gt;Guattari, F. (1995). &lt;i&gt;Chaosmosis: An Ethico-aesthetic Paradigm&lt;/i&gt;. Power Institute of Fine Arts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Nietzsche:2012ta&quot;&gt;Nietzsche, F. (2012). &lt;i&gt;The Dawn of Day&lt;/i&gt;. Project Gutenberg. Retrieved from http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/39955&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Zuboff:1989ul&quot;&gt;Zuboff, S. (1989). &lt;i&gt;In The Age Of The Smart Machine: The Future of Work and Power&lt;/i&gt;. Basic Books.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- [^wonder]: I wonder what he would have made of the current trend of widespread rising educational fees _and_ a global increase of university graduates (at his time, according to the preface by Serge Halimi, the number of students was dropping alarmingly: 81000 in 1930 and only 76000 between 1935 and 1939 [[^students]]).

[^students]: Quoting Eugen Weber, _La France des années 1930_, Fayard, 1995.  --&gt;

&lt;!-- 
&lt;center&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chiens_de_garde.png&quot; alt=&quot;Woof&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:book&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The book I have read is a 2012 edition with a number of useful editorial comments. These are necessary to follow some of the details of Nizan’s arguments because they reference and contextualise philosophers and people from his time. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:book&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:presse&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;[French] http://www.monde-diplomatique.fr/2014/10/HALIMI/50841 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:presse&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/12/30/chiens-de-garde</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/12/30/chiens-de-garde</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building a Static Website with Jekyll and Poole</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost every website provider or blogging system nowadays is tech heavy, relying on dynamic javascript or other dynamic languages to make the web seem more alive. Yet, in many of these solutions, the user and the content provider seem both at the hands of the technology and subservient to its owner. The social aspect becomes &lt;em&gt;entangled&lt;/em&gt; with the tech, instead of complementing each other. It’s the badly called Web 2.0 which pulls on people a magic show to rob them of their money, their time, and sometimes their own private selves. Web 2.0 tries to leave the feeling in your mind that without the technology (and those that are graciously giving it to you), you are outside of the world; you are &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt;. Here, I explain my reasons, and the steps why I have decided to skip the Web 2.0, at least, as much as realistically possible. Maybe the Web 3.0 will be better and more ethical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-reason-behind-static&quot;&gt;The Reason behind Static&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it is in large parts unethical, and almost impossible to evade it. The Web 2.0, even its stupid name, is ever haunting your web surfing, defining your presence online and offline. You have to participate in it,and once you do, you are stuck. Yet, there was a time, and there are still a few places which do not compromise your self with the web itself, which do not turn it into a panopticon at the service of technologically and organisationally superior entities to which would owe your web bodies. Lanier speaks of this well in his book, &lt;em&gt;“You are not a Gadget”&lt;/em&gt;, that there had been an explosion of creativity on both content and form when the web had hit mainstream. He argues, this early explosion is endangered by the social media that format your information, what you should out, determining how things should be interesting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I chose to make this site as a small, voluntarily minimal web presence of mine, and to make it as static as possible. Just as I want to have some say in how I dress, I also want to be able to be an &lt;em&gt;active&lt;/em&gt; actor in revealing myself, or part of myself on the web. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;static-in-one-word-jekyll&quot;&gt;Static in One Word: Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a ruby-based framework which helps you compile a static website. Because you build your own website, Jekyll allows you to influence your presence to a large extent. With it, and the little understanding needed to play with it, I reverse the trend of owing to organisations which do not really care about me, but are interested solely on the data I provide them with. Granted, this blog will be gobbled by dozens of web crawlers, but at least, they won’t be the &lt;em&gt;gatekeepers&lt;/em&gt; of my interaction with my presence. I won’t owe them my web body. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following weeks, I will put detailed explanations of the steps I took to get back my web presence, and the places where I did not succeed. I will also explain the reasoning behind this resistance to become assimilated by services which technologies and algorithms I have neither access nor control over. In contrast, though requiring a bit of techie knowledge, I can have a more &lt;em&gt;transparent engagement&lt;/em&gt; with technologies that mediate the selves I project here. In other future posts, beyond explaining the steps to deploy a static site, I will write some code that can lower the techie barrier and give a nudge to any other who wants to buy himself back on the web. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/09/30/static-comments-poole</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/09/30/static-comments-poole</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Business Models in OS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you find an amazing free or open source software that you think should be working very well, and is in fact, not so much. At least, not as it should. I’ve got two in mind. One is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://practicaltypography.com/&quot;&gt;online book&lt;/a&gt; (and publishing system, please let’s have better sdk docs!) about typography; the other is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://fiduswriter.org/&quot;&gt;publishing system&lt;/a&gt; for academics. They both should work great, have a following, and make headway into institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the academic space, researchers are clinging on word documents which output the same, boring files. Granted, the publishers are partly to be blamed: they seldom accept anything which isn’t a .doc file. Goodbye LaTeX! It’s unfairly labouring if you want to use anything else than an expensive package that holds a monopoly over a closed formatting. That’s where &lt;a href=&quot;http://fiduswriter.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fidus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; comes in. Fidus is a web app which takes text and typesets it in PDF, HTML, or ePub. Makes sense right? Why should the writer worry about how every single element looks? This is the publisher’s job!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other is a great little &lt;a href=&quot;http://practicaltypography.com/&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; with quick advice and context on typography. Yet only about 10% of the 700,000 visitors have left some money behind. It would not have had such publicity if not open source, but still, it’s sad it didn’t get more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t blame so much the people, but the way to contribute to online—especially &lt;em&gt;libre&lt;/em&gt;—content is not satisfactory. There are myriads of online paying systems, but none as open and transparent as should be. I imagine a little button somewhere in the front page that works like flattr in which a small and discretionary amount can be given. Even a pledge system would work well, where people pledge each month a small quantity to share among &lt;em&gt;libre&lt;/em&gt; content, with the money shipped after being given a chance to review and change the pledges. Set aside 10€ to share among your visits, give a little to Linux Mint, give a little to Fidus, give a little to a podcast. If every one who had spent a significant time on hoe typography website had payed a minuscule amount, the project would be much more successful. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if the GNUs are doing something to facilitate this?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/08/21/Sometimes-you-find-an-amazing-free-or-open-source</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/08/21/Sometimes-you-find-an-amazing-free-or-open-source</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Github (User-)Pages and Jekyll Now for Blogs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had wanted to do this a long time ago, but had so little time. Finally,  thanks to the really simple &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2014/08/01/build-blog-jekyll-github-pages/&quot;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; from Barry Clark, the developer behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/barryclark/jekyll-now&quot;&gt;Jekyll Now&lt;/a&gt;, I can start blogging here already. Jekyll Now is an already built structure of Jekyll with template included, so just fork it and change it. It’s really simple. Had thought of using &lt;a href=&quot;http://jaspervdj.be/hakyll/&quot;&gt;Hakyll&lt;/a&gt;, and I will, but shall wait for the Raspberry Pi to arrive and build my new server first. 
The reason for doing this is the simplicity behind static sites. I was (am) getting fed up of the flurry of super, ultra, widgets in your face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks Barry! I can now read papers and do &lt;em&gt;my thing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/03/03/Hello-World</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/03/03/Hello-World</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>