<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>curtomil (crtml)</title>
    <description>Socia(l / ble) Scientist</description>
    <link>https://curtomil.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="https://curtomil.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Building a Static Website with Jekyll and Poole</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost every website provider or blogging system nowadays is tech heavy, relying on dynamic javascript or other dynamic languages to make the web seem more alive. Yet, in many of these solutions, the user and the content provider seem both at the hands of the technology and subservient to its owner. The social aspect becomes &lt;em&gt;entangled&lt;/em&gt; with the tech, instead of complementing each other. It’s the badly called Web 2.0 which pulls on people a magic show to rob them of their money, their time, and sometimes their own private selves. Web 2.0 tries to leave the feeling in your mind that without the technology (and those that are graciously giving it to you), you are outside of the world; you are &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt;. Here, I explain my reasons, and the steps why I have decided to skip the Web 2.0, at least, as much as realistically possible. Maybe the Web 3.0 will be better and more ethical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-reason-behind-static&quot;&gt;The Reason behind Static&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it is in large parts unethical, and almost impossible to evade it. The Web 2.0, even its stupid name, is ever haunting your web surfing, defining your presence online and offline. You have to participate in it,and once you do, you are stuck. Yet, there was a time, and there are still a few places which do not compromise your self with the web itself, which do not turn it into a panopticon at the service of technologically and organisationally superior entities to which would owe your web bodies. Lanier speaks of this well in his book, &lt;em&gt;“You are not a Gadget”&lt;/em&gt;, that there had been an explosion of creativity on both content and form when the web had hit mainstream. He argues, this early explosion is endangered by the social media that format your information, what you should out, determining how things should be interesting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I chose to make this site as a small, voluntarily minimal web presence of mine, and to make it as static as possible. Just as I want to have some say in how I dress, I also want to be able to be an &lt;em&gt;active&lt;/em&gt; actor in revealing myself, or part of myself on the web. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;static-in-one-word-jekyll&quot;&gt;Static in One Word: Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a ruby-based framework which helps you compile a static website. Because you build your own website, Jekyll allows you to influence your presence to a large extent. With it, and the little understanding needed to play with it, I reverse the trend of owing to organisations which do not really care about me, but are interested solely on the data I provide them with. Granted, this blog will be gobbled by dozens of web crawlers, but at least, they won’t be the &lt;em&gt;gatekeepers&lt;/em&gt; of my interaction with my presence. I won’t owe them my web body. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following weeks, I will put detailed explanations of the steps I took to get back my web presence, and the places where I did not succeed. I will also explain the reasoning behind this resistance to become assimilated by services which technologies and algorithms I have neither access nor control over. In contrast, though requiring a bit of techie knowledge, I can have a more &lt;em&gt;transparent engagement&lt;/em&gt; with technologies that mediate the selves I project here. In other future posts, beyond explaining the steps to deploy a static site, I will write some code that can lower the techie barrier and give a nudge to any other who wants to buy himself back on the web. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/09/30/static-comments-poole</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/09/30/static-comments-poole</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Business Models in OS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you find an amazing free or open source software that you think should be working very well, and is in fact, not so much. At least, not as it should. I’ve got two in mind. One is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://practicaltypography.com/&quot;&gt;online book&lt;/a&gt; (and publishing system, please let’s have better sdk docs!) about typography; the other is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://fiduswriter.org/&quot;&gt;publishing system&lt;/a&gt; for academics. They both should work great, have a following, and make headway into institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the academic space, researchers are clinging on word documents which output the same, boring files. Granted, the publishers are partly to be blamed: they seldom accept anything which isn’t a .doc file. Goodbye LaTeX! It’s unfairly labouring if you want to use anything else than an expensive package that holds a monopoly over a closed formatting. That’s where &lt;a href=&quot;http://fiduswriter.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fidus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; comes in. Fidus is a web app which takes text and typesets it in PDF, HTML, or ePub. Makes sense right? Why should the writer worry about how every single element looks? This is the publisher’s job!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other is a great little &lt;a href=&quot;http://practicaltypography.com/&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; with quick advice and context on typography. Yet only about 10% of the 700,000 visitors have left some money behind. It would not have had such publicity if not open source, but still, it’s sad it didn’t get more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t blame so much the people, but the way to contribute to online—especially &lt;em&gt;libre&lt;/em&gt;—content is not satisfactory. There are myriads of online paying systems, but none as open and transparent as should be. I imagine a little button somewhere in the front page that works like flattr in which a small and discretionary amount can be given. Even a pledge system would work well, where people pledge each month a small quantity to share among &lt;em&gt;libre&lt;/em&gt; content, with the money shipped after being given a chance to review and change the pledges. Set aside 10€ to share among your visits, give a little to Linux Mint, give a little to Fidus, give a little to a podcast. If every one who had spent a significant time on hoe typography website had payed a minuscule amount, the project would be much more successful. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if the GNUs are doing something to facilitate this?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/08/21/Sometimes-you-find-an-amazing-free-or-open-source</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/08/21/Sometimes-you-find-an-amazing-free-or-open-source</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Github (User-)Pages and Jekyll Now for Blogs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had wanted to do this a long time ago, but had so little time. Finally,  thanks to the really simple &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2014/08/01/build-blog-jekyll-github-pages/&quot;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; from Barry Clark, the developer behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/barryclark/jekyll-now&quot;&gt;Jekyll Now&lt;/a&gt;, I can start blogging here already. Jekyll Now is an already built structure of Jekyll with template included, so just fork it and change it. It’s really simple. Had thought of using &lt;a href=&quot;http://jaspervdj.be/hakyll/&quot;&gt;Hakyll&lt;/a&gt;, and I will, but shall wait for the Raspberry Pi to arrive and build my new server first. 
The reason for doing this is the simplicity behind static sites. I was (am) getting fed up of the flurry of super, ultra, widgets in your face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks Barry! I can now read papers and do &lt;em&gt;my thing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/03/03/Hello-World</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://curtomil.github.io/blog/2014/03/03/Hello-World</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>